http://www.newswise.com/privacy

Privacy Policy
multimedia
my favorites
Newswise is committed to providing its online users with services and information in an efficient and secure manner. This privacy policy explains what personal information is collected on newswise.com (the “Newswise website”) from users of Newswise’s various online services, how that information is used and what measures Newswise takes to safeguard its users’ privacy. This privacy policy was updated May 25, 2018, to reflect compliance with the EU GDPR.
What personal information is collected on the Newswise website?
When you register, we collect information as needed to provide you with particular services depending on your account type. We may request or require some or all of the following information: name, e-mail address, telephone, media affiliation, organization profile, beat (for journalists) and categories of interest.
In addition, Newswise may provide a secure payment gateway for clients, where billing data may be requested and encrypted. This information is used solely for the processing of the specific purchase and is not used for any other purpose. Newswise’s method of collecting and processing credit card information is PCI-DSS compliant.We do not store credit card information.
How does Newswise use the information collected on the Newswise website?
Information about individual users collected on the Newswise websites is used for internal business purposes, including customizing services, contacting members regarding submissions, and responding to requests for information. On occasion, Newswise may use this information to inform you of news, service upgrades or new services or products that may be of particular interest to you.
Newswise tracks aggregate statistics regarding usage of the website and provides this anonymous information to members, clients, advertisers and for other lawful purposes. We do not provide data on the behavior of specific users.
Newswise will not send you unsolicited email. You may subscribe to email Newswires when you register or by editing your account preferences. You may by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any newsletter.
Does Newswise provide personal information collected on the Newswise website to third parties?
Newswise does not sell, trade or rent personal information collected online and will not knowingly disclose any individual personal information to third parties except as follows:
(1) In order to provide you with requested services, Newswise may provide contact or other necessary information to affiliated companies. For example, if you are a journalist and you use the Expert Query service, Newswise may provide your email address and/or phone number to the identified expert in order to facilitate initial contact between you and the expert;
(2) When disclosure is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with the rights (including property rights) or safety of other users or third parties or of Newswise; and
(3) When Newswise reasonably believes that disclosure is required by law or to comply with legal process served on Newswise.
How can I change or update the information I provide at the Newswise website?
Newswise offers you the opportunity to change or update your profile information at any time by visiting, logging in, and clicking on “My Account”.
For our Newswise newswire digest services, you may unsubscribe at any time by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link on any email received.
Newswise maintains a media database containing personal information on EU media contacts, and such individuals can have such information removed from our database. This information does not include sensitive information such as data about race, sexual orientation, or religion. If you wish to remove your personal information from our database, please write to:
If you have questions, comments or requests relating to this Privacy Policy, or wish to opt out of any usage of your information as described herein, please e-mail us at
Does the Newswise website use cookies?
Newswise sends a “cookie” to your computer that contains an identification number that is unique to the computer you are using. We use this cookie to provide you with a continuous experience, and for us to record how our service is being used.
As is done with most web sites, we log each visit to each web page. A log entry can contain information typically found in the “header” of your web browser’s request such as the browser type you used, your Internet Protocol address, and the date and time of day. We may also log your cookie’s identification number and the URL of the last site you visited. If you are a journalist, your journal affiliations will be noted in the record of hits for an article, and shared with our clients as an aggregated statistic. Statistics for individual journalists’ visits are not shared. Log information is important for security, audit, quality improvement, as well as for monitoring the health and use of our service.
Please note that if you click on a link to a third-party website from the Newswise website, the linked-to site may have different policies and practices with regard to cookies and Newswise has no control over and is not responsible for such policies or practices. You should always consult the privacy policy governing any website you visit on the Internet for complete information about their policies and practices.
What security measures does Newswise take to safeguard its online users’ privacy?
Information you submit at a Newswise website upon registration for specific services is password protected so that the only parties who have access to the information besides Newswise and its agents are the member entity and its employees.
In addition, individual employees of members will receive individual accounts and passwords to use when they log on to submit press releases online.
In order to protect the integrity of the password system, members should refrain from disclosing passwords and immediately change any passwords that may have been compromised.
Newswise will never ask you for your password by email, so members and their employees should not respond to unsolicited e-mail requests asking for password information even if such requests appear to be from Newswise.
Please be advised that no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secured. Newswise is committed to protecting users’ personal information, but cannot guarantee or warrant the security of this information when it is sent to or through the Newswise website. Transmission of such information is therefore at the risk of the user.
Usernames and Passwords
Users may register with
Once usernames and passwords (the “Login Information”) are issued to users (the “Authorized Users”), the Authorized Users accept full responsibility for the use of the Login Information. The Authorized User may not, under any circumstances, release their Login Information to any other person for any reason, and is required to keep the Login Information strictly confidential. If any breach of security, theft or loss, or unauthorized disclosure of the Login Information occurs, the Authorized User must immediately notify Newswise of such security breach.
Privacy policy updates
This policy will be updated from time to time as necessary to add new services and functions. Newswise will provide you with notice of any changes or updates to this policy.
close
search
Services
Contact Us
Demo
Login
Sections keyboard_arrow_down
Latest News
Featured:
Featured:
Featured:
Featured:
BizWire
In the Workplace
Story Ideas:
Featured:
BizWire
Featured:
DailyWire
Featured:
LifeWire
Featured:
MedWire
Featured:
